# **Ifrah Mohamed**

(206) 240-3203 | Ifrah@uw.edu | linkedin.com/in/ifrahm22 | ifrahm.github.io | Seattle, WA

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Washington**

Sept 2018 – Anticipated June 2022

• B.S in Informatics (Human-Computer Interaction), Information School, GPA: 3.47

## SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Programming: JavaScript • Node.js • Java • Python • R • PHP/MySQL • HTML • CSS

Design: Interaction Design • Use Cases • Wireframes • Rapid Prototyping • User Personas

Research: Affinity Diagrams • Customer Experience and Journey Maps • Contextual Inquiry • Survey & Interviews

Tools: Figma • Marvel

Courses: Computer Programing • Web Programing • Statistical Computing • Design Methods • Information Systems Analysis and Design

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Microsoft, Al Intern

June 2018 - Aug 2018

- Created data visualization to display traffic flow in intersections from live camera streams in Power Bi
- Collaborated with fellow teammates to create a program featuring image video analytics that reads traffic lights in partnership with the city of Bellevue. Presented project content at two showcases at end of internship

#### Educurious, Marketing Intern

July 2017 - Aug 2017

- Facilitated focus groups with youth participants to investigate the most effective outreach platforms
- Executed and launched email campaign to 1,500 youth opportunity youth interns to spread awareness
- Collaborated with supervisors to create and analyze surveys, resulting in valuable youth insight on the program

#### Filipino Community Center, STEM Intern

July 2015 - Aug 2015

- Assisted and provided focus to the startup of the STEM program at Filipino Community Center.
- Collaborated with community center to implement a graffiti art program and robotics program with a variety of lessons and activities to further engage the youth

## **PROJECTS**

#### Life in Lockdown — Front-End Developer

Mar 2020 - June 2020

Front-end developer on a 24hr hackathon collaboration project that gives a holistic view of the problems people face in quarantine
using Unreal Engine 4.

#### Furmilliar — UX Designer

Mar 2020 - June 2020

Designed a low-fidelity mobile application using Marvel to track stray cats and collect data in support of feral cat research.

## A Helping Hand — UX Designer/Research

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Lead UX designer in creating a high-fidelity social platform using Figma to help seniors and their caretakers with daily
activities. Drove ideation from general platform to being more user tailored through extensive user research on seniors housing
decision making

## **LEADERSHIP**

## National Society of Black Engineers, Region VI Finance Chair

May 2020 - Present

- Contacting and fostering meaningful partnerships with corporate sponsors for the Annual Fall Regional Conference
- Providing financial advice to over 50 collegiate chapters in the region

#### National Society of Black Engineers, Programs Chair (UW Chapter)

Sept 2019 - June 2020

- Providing resources and mission driven guidance to the members to excel academically and professionally
- Planning various events that required budgeting for location, catering, keynote speakers and reaching out to donors.
- Overseeing all UW NSBE programs committees (Recruitment committee, Graduation committee, etc.)
- Working closely with the PCI/Torch chair operations

## Somali Student Association, Internal Development (UW chapter)

Sept 2019 - July 2020

- Led general meetings to foster friendship and good relations among SSA members and promote upcoming events.
- Brainstormed and implemented end to end meeting plans to increase engagement.
- Coordinated administrative tasks to ensure the success of regular meetings